<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: real talk | Martha Kelly]]></title>
  <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/categories/real-talk/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-27T14:00:54-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Martha Kelly]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[my actual response to the anonymous idiots on the internet]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/09/27/my-actual-response-to-the-anonymous-idiots-on-the-internet/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-27T13:16:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/09/27/my-actual-response-to-the-anonymous-idiots-on-the-internet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My previous post was a bit tongue in cheek, and honestly, it was just so absurd I couldn't <a href="http://i.chzbgr.com/completestore/2012/3/8/eb9c0160-78f4-4f08-8a03-34bbdb39a54e.jpg">halp</a> myself but share it with you.</p>

<p>After some reflection this is my actual response. My response to the anonymous idiots? No, friend. This is my response to you. These are a few things I'd like you to remember if you find yourself in a similar situation as I did in the Coursera forums today.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Don’t waste your energy trying to educate or change opinions; go over, under, through, and opinions will change organically when you’re the boss. Or they won’t. Who cares? Do your thing, and don’t care if they like it.”</p><footer><strong>Tina Fey</strong> <cite>Bossypants</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>“So, my unsolicited advice to women in the workplace is this. When faced with sexism, or ageism, or lookism, or even really aggressive Buddhism, ask yourself the following question: “Is this person in between me and what I want to do?” If the answer is no, ignore it and move on. Your energy is better used doing your work and outpacing people that way. Then, when you’re in charge, don’t hire the people who were jerky to you.”</p><footer><strong>Tina Fey</strong> <cite>Bossypants</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>The best thing you can possibly do with your life is to tackle the m!therf&amp;$ing sh!* out of it.</p><footer><strong>Sugar</strong> <cite>therumpus.net</cite></footer></blockquote></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
