<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: inspiration | Martha Kelly]]></title>
  <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/categories/inspiration/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-28T15:33:45-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Martha Kelly]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zoe Pablo: role model for women]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/08/01/zoe-pablo-role-model-for-young-women/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-01T09:23:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/08/01/zoe-pablo-role-model-for-young-women</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I found this article from Zoe Pablo, Olympic weight lifter, [ <a href="http://zoepablosmith.wordpress.com/2012/07/23/thanks-but-no-thanks/">article source</a> ] today and am so excited to share my favorite highlights with you. Women are marginalized by how they look and quite frankly <em>it's complete bullshit.</em></p>

<p><blockquote><p>The obvious choice of slander when talking about female weightlifting is “how unfeminine, girls shouldn’t be strong or have muscles, this is wrong”. And maybe they’re right… in the Victorian era.</p><footer><strong>Zoe Pablo</strong> <cite>Thanks (but No Thanks…)</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>we don’t lift weights in order to look hot, especially for the likes of men like that. What makes them think that we even WANT them to find us attractive? If you do, thanks very much, we’re flattered. But if you don’t, why do you really need to voice this opinion in the first place, and what makes you think we actually give a toss that you, personally, do not find us attractive? What do you want us to do? Shall we stop weightlifting, amend our diet in order to completely get rid of our ‘manly’ muscles, and become housewives in the sheer hope that one day you will look more favourably upon us and we might actually have a shot with you?!</p><footer><strong>Zoe Pablo</strong> <cite>Thanks (but No Thanks…)</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>xoxo</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linda Liukas - What every girl needs to know about programming]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/05/30/what-every-girl-needs-to-know-about-programming/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-30T12:57:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/05/30/what-every-girl-needs-to-know-about-programming</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><iframe width="640" height="510" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/_rkkFdQeBlA " frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<h3>Highlights:</h3>

<ul>
<li>The low number of girls and women in programming is a systematic problem, something fundamental is missing</li>
<li>Teenage girls have a massive amount of crazy and creative energy, they <em>should</em> learn to code</li>
<li>Coding is not lonely and it's not mathematical</li>
<li>We are so stuck in semantics and exclusion that we can't function as a community, it's no longer fun and enjoyable</li>
<li>It's up to us to create a new culture of development - one that is fun and focuses on creating and building</li>
</ul>


<h3>My thoughts:</h3>

<p>Linda Liukas <em>thank you, thank you, thank you</em>.</p>

<p>Right now (in technology) girls are rewarded when they fit in with the boys, but what about the girls that don't and just want to be <em>themselves</em>? The outlets for them are few and far between.</p>

<h3>Not convinced? Try thinking about it this way:</h3>

<p>There are many girls and women frustrated by their experiences in programming, but men are not equally as frustrated. There are few girls and women pursing technology, but there is an abundance of white males. <em>This means it's not the same situation</em>. There's no reason at all that girls (and boys for that matter!) who like shoes, nail polish, and miu miu handbags can't build amazing products that get just as much recognition.</p>

<h3>What can we do to help?</h3>

<p>Girls need more inclusion and more role models (how many female Mark Zuckerbergs can you think of?). Support organizations that make building and learning about technology fun (for example, <a href="http://railsgirls.com/">Rails Girls</a>). This should go without saying, but you should end any RTFM shaming, sexual/objectifying images, and demeaning jokes in the tech communities and workplaces you're a part of.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>If I should ever have a daughter or a son I would like them to see the world of technology through this lens of magical culture.</p><footer><strong>Linda Liukas</strong> <cite>What Every Girl Needs to Know About Programming</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>Please check out <a href="http://railsgirls.com/">Rails Girls</a>, and Linda - thank you.</p>

<p>(also, check out <a href="http://www.lindaliukas.fi/">Linda's website!</a>)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[inspired]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/05/25/daily-inspiration/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-25T11:58:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/05/25/daily-inspiration</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><blockquote><p>As one of the few female students studying automotive design, I naively felt the need to blend in with my male classmates and find a way to minimize being seen as the only girl. I contemplated signing all of my design sketches as “Chris Park” instead of “Christine Park,” but in the back of my mind I knew it didn’t feel right. My professor offered some great guidance by telling me, “Be who you are.” I learned to embrace the fact that my uniqueness helped set me apart.</p></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>Today, working in an industry where there are few women, I can bring a different perspective to the table. But, I never want my gender to define me. Instead, my work will speak for itself, and I now know the key is being comfortable in my own skin.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Christine Park - <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/jennagoudreau/2012/05/25/how-i-went-from-art-school-to-gms-senior-cadillac-designer-by-age-28/">How I Went From Art School To GM's Senior Cadillac Designer By Age 28</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
