<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Martha Kelly]]></title>
  <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-09T11:16:35-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Martha Kelly]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ladies hack day - what to expect]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2013/05/09/ladies-hack-day-what-to-expect/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-09T10:58:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2013/05/09/ladies-hack-day-what-to-expect</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone,</p>

<p>I am excited beyond words about this Saturday. Nashville (and beyond) came together as a community to make this happen, and It has been a joy to watch this come together.</p>

<p>The <strong>biggest of all thank yous</strong> go to our sponsors:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://myemma.com/">Emma</a></li>
<li><a href="http://github.com/">Github</a></li>
<li><a href="http://skillcrush.com/">Skillcrush</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.vaco.com/">Vaco</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.moontoast.com/">Moontoast</a></li>
<li><a href="http://metova.com/">Metova</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.cowanbenefit.com/">Cowan Benefit Services</a></li>
<li>Laurie Kalmanson, User Experience Architect</li>
<li>Sharon Wong, Software Engineer</li>
<li>Candy Vaughn, ABR, Keller Williams Realty</li>
<li>T Scot Clausing, Developer</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>What is Ladies’ Hack Day?</strong></p>

<p>Ladies’ Hack Day is a day for women and girls (and men and boys) to come together and celebrate women in computing. Programming is not lonely, it is not scary, it is not mathematical! We’ll have a beginner course in HTML, another beginner course in JS, and an advanced course in Python. We’ll also have a separate Minecraft track to learn about modding Minecraft! You can come and go as you like the entire day.</p>

<p><strong>Who can come?</strong></p>

<p>Anyone! Hopefully you RSVP’d but if you didn’t, just show up, we’re happy to have you. We’ll have children as young as 5 and adults in their 50s!</p>

<p><strong>What will we do?</strong></p>

<p>In the beginner tracks we’ll build an interactive e-card for Mother’s Day. I’m reminded of this quote, “Biology is the least of what makes someone a mother.” - Oprah Winfrey. The card could be for any person in your life you want to say thank you to.</p>

<p>In the advanced track we will build a Twitter bot for good in Python (more info below).</p>

<p><strong>Schedule:</strong></p>

<p><strong>9:45-10:45</strong></p>

<p>Coffee by <a href="http://www.bevecoffee.com/">Beve</a>, provided by Vaco and Moontoast</p>

<p><strong>10:45 - 11:00</strong></p>

<p>Opening remarks</p>

<p><strong>11:00 - ??</strong>
<strong>Intro to Minecraft modding</strong></p>

<p>We&#8217;ll have a few helpful folks available to get you started with modding Minecraft.</p>

<p><strong>11:15 - 12:15</strong>
<strong>Intro to HTML!</strong></p>

<p>We’ll learn about HTML, what it is, and how to write it. You’ll leave with a finished card to send to someone you love (you write the HTML, we’ll provide the CSS and JS). You’re free to Hack on this project or anything you want for the rest of the day. We also encourage you to stick around and watch the JS presentation, even if just to observe.</p>

<p><strong>12:30 - 1:30</strong>
<strong>lunch!</strong></p>

<p>Quiches, salads, and hummus by Whole Foods. Provided by Github and Metova.</p>

<p><strong>1:45 - 2:45</strong>
<strong>Intro to JavaScript</strong></p>

<p>We’ll build upon the HTML track but write the JavaScript interaction from scratch. We’ll learn what JavaScript is, what jQuery is, and how we can use both of these languages to bend the web to our will.</p>

<p><strong>CUPCAKE BREAK - cupcakes from Cupcake Collection</strong></p>

<p><strong>3:00 - 5:00</strong>
<strong>Intro to Python</strong></p>

<p>Together we’ll build a twitter bot, but for good! We’ll learn about Python, how a server side language differs from a client side language, and how to use Python and the Twitter API to build an optimistic twitter bot. We’ll walk through the code line by line, you just bring an idea for a cute twitter bot! (my example: @instacompliment - a bot that searches Twitter for the words “bad day” and then sends that user a compliment)</p>

<p><strong>5:00 - 6:00</strong>
<strong>Show and tell</strong></p>

<p>If you’d like to show off your work, this is your chance! This is definitely not required, just encouraged.</p>

<p>I can’t wait to see you on Saturday!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Open Letter To the Nashville Tech Community]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2013/03/10/an-open-letter-to-the-nashville-tech-community/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-10T18:39:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2013/03/10/an-open-letter-to-the-nashville-tech-community</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I realize many of you don&#8217;t know me.</p>

<p>I would really like you to know me, and I would like to get to know you.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m Martha. I&#8217;m a programmer. I desperately love what I do.</p>

<p>I have opinions. <em>You might not agree with them.</em> That is okay.</p>

<p>When I criticize the community, it&#8217;s often the result of a thousand little cuts that compound over time. I speak up because I want things to change. I honestly care about you. I care about this community. The women and men I&#8217;ve chosen to have deeper relationships with, I&#8217;m indebted to you and I genuinely care about you.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s time for me to be honest with you.</p>

<p>Here are things I can&#8217;t do:</p>

<ul>
<li>Read sexist, gendered, racist text in tech articles or PR in Nashville</li>
<li>Listen to sexist, gendered, racist discussion in the tech community in Nashville</li>
<li>Tolerate sexist memes or comments in Nashville IRC channels</li>
<li>Feel uncomfortable at tech meet ups</li>
<li>Be sexually harassed at tech meet ups</li>
<li>Be the only woman in the room</li>
</ul>


<p>Here are things I can do:</p>

<ul>
<li>Be myself</li>
<li>Be your friend</li>
<li>Have an opinion (it might be different from yours!)</li>
<li>Speak up when I have a problem with something</li>
<li>Make Nashville Tech better for all women (and people)</li>
<li>Empower your female friends/coworkers/family members to learn to code</li>
<li>Teach you something, and learn something from you</li>
</ul>


<p>Since we’re being honest, here’s what I want:</p>

<ul>
<li>I want to act like a woman and be treated with respect for that</li>
<li>I want to feel comfortable in my own skin</li>
<li>I don&#8217;t want to feel threatened</li>
<li>I want my colleagues to back me up if I feel uncomfortable about something</li>
<li>I want to feel safe enough to be myself</li>
</ul>


<p>Why do I want this? Because I want to live and work and play with you all and do what I love with you (more coding! And, perhaps beer drinking?). I also just want female friends, mentors, teachers, and advocates that are interested in the same things I am. I want women to feel comfortable pursuing and working in technical jobs in Nashville. Right now Nashville is an uncomfortable place to be a woman in tech.</p>

<p>If I give criticism of the community, it&#8217;s because I want something better for everyone.</p>

<p>I made a comment like <a href="https://twitter.com/marthakelly/status/310065932087205888">this</a>.</p>

<p>I was shocked to see this response:</p>

<ul>
<li>&#8220;can I still use the word &#8216;human&#8217; to describe homo sapiens of all genders?&#8221;</li>
<li>&#8220;human does have &#8216;man&#8217; in it&#8221;</li>
<li>&#8220;womyn if you ask my sisters&#8221;</li>
<li>(when asked to meet at a bar referencing this situation) &#8220;good. [this bar] it is. I&#8217;ll be sure to bring my vagina.&#8221;</li>
<li>&#8220;stand down. If you wanted to make a point then you were free to make your point. He made his. He doesn&#8217;t need you to validate or &#8220;correct&#8221; it. Stay on topic fer chrissakes.”</li>
<li>“[He wrote that word] because that&#8217;s the word he chose to use. It&#8217;s not about this topic. Grind elsewhere.”</li>
<li>“You are the problem, not the solution here.”</li>
<li>“Don&#8217;t expect anyone to support you when you can&#8217;t be cohesive and want to elevate you own agenda at the expense of the core issue.”</li>
</ul>


<p>For the record, I received a heartwarming amount of encouragement (in private).</p>

<p>The honest truth is I don&#8217;t feel safe or happy here.</p>

<p>So, I&#8217;m creating a community on my terms. Nashville Women&#8217;s STEAM Group is my microcosm of what I want Nashville to be.</p>

<p>The last Saturday of every month we&#8217;re opening up Code Day to everyone. Our inaugural meeting is March 30th (more details to come).</p>

<p>Everyone is invited. We&#8217;d absolutely love to have you.</p>

<p>We do have ground rules, and they may seem <a href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/06/04/hacker-school-day-one/">familiar</a>.</p>

<p>1) no saying “well actually”
2) no feigning surprise
3) no backseat driving
4) no subtle sexism, racism, or any discrimination</p>

<p>I hope to see you there.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[authenticity]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2013/01/23/authenticity/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-23T20:47:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2013/01/23/authenticity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>I found that my lack of authenticity actually prevented people from getting close to me.  I wasn’t vulnerable.  I didn’t want others to see my mistakes or flaws, and I did everything I could to cover them up.  I would lie if I thought the truth would hurt.  I even had two online profiles – my work profile and my real profile. </p><p>And then everything changed.  </p><p>I don’t know if it was an efficiency thing (maintaining 2 separate identities was hard), or if I just decided that I was tired of trying to project “awesome”, and since reality was “pretty darn good” people would just have to accept what I had to offer.  I was going to be me. </p><p>But to my surprise instead of the world settling for me – they embraced it.</p><footer><strong>Kate Matsudaira</strong> <cite><a href='http://katemats.com/authenticity-path-to-success/'>katemats.com/&hellip;</a></cite></footer></blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[how browsers work]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2013/01/21/how-browsers-work/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-21T14:52:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2013/01/21/how-browsers-work</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You know a bit about HTML, CSS, and JavaScript but do you now how a browser gets and uses these files to display a website?</p>

<p>A browser has a UI (user interface) that most commonly includes an address bar, back/forward button, and reload button. Sometimes developers refer to this as the &#8220;chrome&#8221; (little &#8220;c&#8221;, not Chrome by Google) of a browser. When you navigate to a URL in the address bar you are making a &#8220;request&#8221; for the content at that URL.</p>

<p><img src="http://marthakelly.github.com/images/google-chrome.png"></p>

<p>That URL you typed into the address bar maps to an IP address. This is called a DNS lookup. DNS stands for &#8220;Domain Name System&#8221; and it maps numeric computer addresses to human readable names. All computers have an IP address. You can find out your personal computer&#8217;s IP address by typing &#8220;ifconfig&#8221; into your terminal window and looking for the number that is displayed in dot decimal format, such as 000.000.000.000. (Note that 127.0.0.1 is used in your computer internally to refer to itself).</p>

<p>For example, one IP address for Google is 74.125.134.102. You can enter 74.125.134.102 in the address bar and it will show the contents at www.google.com.</p>

<p>Once the browser has the IP address it sends an HTTP request to the web server at that address. HTTP stands for &#8220;Hypertext Transfer Protocol&#8221; and is used to facilitate requests from your client (the browser) and responses from the server. In our case the response is HTML from the web server at www.google.com.</p>

<p>As this HTML response is being sent to your browser, the browser&#8217;s rendering engine is displaying the requested content on your screen. To accomplish this the rendering engine &#8220;parses&#8221; the HTML and creates a DOM tree.</p>

<p>To illustrate this, the rendering engine takes this HTML response:</p>

<pre><code>// Simplified Google.com markup
&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt; 
&lt;html&gt; 
    &lt;head&gt; 
        &lt;title&gt;Google&lt;/title&gt;  
        &lt;link rel="stylesheet" href="css/style.css" 
            type="text/css" /&gt; 
    &lt;/head&gt; 
    &lt;body class="home"&gt; 
        &lt;h1&gt;Google&lt;/h1&gt; 
        &lt;img alt="Google" src="http://marthakelly.github.com/logos/google.jpg"&gt;
        &lt;input&gt;
        &lt;button&gt;Google Search&lt;/button&gt;
    &lt;/body&gt; 
&lt;/html&gt; 
</code></pre>

<p>And turns it (conceptually) into a DOM tree <em>like</em> this:<br/>
(photoshop is being a PITA! I&#8217;ll try to add an appropriate graph later)</p>

<p><img src="http://www.w3schools.com/htmldom/htmltree.gif"></p>

<p>The browser then parses style data (CSS or inline styles) and together with the HTML it constructs a render tree. The render tree displays rectangles (that represent divs, paragraphs, headlines, etc.) with a few visual attributes such as color and size dimensions. These rectangles are displayed in order on the page. Next, the browser lays out the contents in the position they will appear in the browser. The last step is &#8220;painting&#8221; where the elements are drawn on the screen.</p>

<p>As the browser is rendering the HTML it will find tags (like our link tag and our img tag) that require files from other URLs. The browser will send a request to the web server to get each of these files.</p>

<p>(Note: some interesting things happen in regards to caching but I&#8217;m overlooking them for now. I&#8217;ll include them in a later post).</p>

<h3>Notes About Major Browsers</h3>

<p>Firefox uses the Gecko rendering engine, a Mozilla product. Both Safari and Chrome (and now Opera on mobile?) use Webkit as a rendering engine, which is an open source project. IE uses the Trident rendering engine.</p>

<p>If you&#8217;re curious (as I am!) here&#8217;s the world wide browser market share in 2012:</p>

<p>IE, 54.13%<br/>
Firefox, 19.99%<br/>
Chrome, 18.55%<br/>
Safari, 5.21%<br/>
Opera, 1.63%<br/>
Other, 0.49%</p>

<p>That was a quick and dirty overview. As the weeks go on I&#8217;ll dive deeply into each component, even getting down through the deeper layers of the network reference model. If you&#8217;re not sure what that is, you&#8217;ll know soon! (Hint: it&#8217;s how all those 0s and 1s travel over the wires).</p>

<p>Sources:<br/>
<a href="http://taligarsiel.com/Projects/howbrowserswork1.htm">http://taligarsiel.com/Projects/howbrowserswork1.htm</a><br/>
<a href="http://bgr.com/2012/11/01/browser-market-share-october-2012-chrome-internet-explorerer/">http://bgr.com/2012/11/01/browser-market-share-october-2012-chrome-internet-explorerer/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Many Tamagotchis were harmed in the making of this presentation]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2013/01/11/many-tamagotchis-were-harmed/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-11T08:51:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2013/01/11/many-tamagotchis-were-harmed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;d like to introduce you to one of my newfound heros, Natalie Silvanovich.</p>

<iframe width="640" height="510" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/WOJfUcCOhJ0 " frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p></p>

<p>Natalie Silvanovich is a &#8220;professional hacker&#8221; and Security Researcher. She tests <a href="http://www.rim.com/">RIM</a> products to prevent attackers from getting the information of BlackBerry users. She studied Electrical Engineering in school (although she claims it&#8217;s been a long time since she&#8217;s been in school), and in her spare time she hacks Tamagotchis.</p>

<p>Natalie is super clever, persistent, and funny. Not to mention my main motivation in signing up for <a href="https://www.coursera.org/course/eefun">Fundamentals of Electrical Engineering</a> which starts in only 10 days. Now, who wants to take the course with me?</p>

<p>Check out her posts/projects/hacking at <a href="http://www.kwartzlab.ca/author/natalies/">Kwartzlab</a> and follow her on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/natashenka">@natashenka</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[where have you been??]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/12/18/where-have-you-been/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-18T17:45:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/12/18/where-have-you-been</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Why, adjusting to (and just soaking in) Etsy life of course! It has been an astonishing amount of time since my last post, and I&#8217;m happy to report it&#8217;s been for great reasons.</p>

<h3>Let&#8217;s catch up</h3>

<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/nashSTEM/">Nashville Women&#8217;s STEM</a> group is going strong. We&#8217;ve been meeting regularly and have big plans for 2013:</p>

<ul>
<li>Special fundraising to bring in leadership training</li>
<li><a href="http://katemats.com/">Kate Matsudaira</a> blog post discussion series</li>
<li>Open Sourcing an Arduino project guide for young women and men</li>
<li>AP Computer Science test prep for young women</li>
</ul>


<p><strong> BREAKING NEWS!! </strong> I&#8217;m organizing <a href="http://nashville.nerdnite.com/">Nerd Nite Nashville</a>!
What is Nerd Nite you ask?</p>

<blockquote><p>We all know that learning is more fun when you’re drinking with friends and colleagues. Thus, Nerd Nite is a monthly event held in more than 50 cities across the globe during which several folks give 18-21-minute fun-yet-informative presentations across all disciplines – while the audience drinks along.</p><footer><strong>Nerd Nite</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.nerdnite.com'>www.nerdnite.com/&hellip;</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p></p>

<p>Here are a few of my favorite Nerd Nite presentations:</p>

<iframe width="" height="" src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/27851814 " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p></p>

<iframe width="" height="" src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/19716014 " frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p></p>

<p>Do you like 1) drinking with friends and colleagues 2) presenting and nerding out while drinking in front of your friends and colleagues? 3) are near Nashville? If so, email me: <a href="mailto:mk.girdler@gmail.com">mk.girdler@gmail.com</a></p>

<p>Lastly, If you haven&#8217;t already seen this consider it required reading - <a href="http://www.kitchensoap.com/2012/10/25/on-being-a-senior-engineer/">&#8220;On Being a Senior Engineer&#8221;</a> by John Allspaw SVP of Technical Operations at Etsy.</p>

<p>Notable soundbite:</p>

<blockquote><p>You don’t wake up one day and you are “senior” just because your title reflects that upon a promotion. Senior engineers don’t know everything. They’re not perfect in their technical knowledge, and they’re OK with that.</p><footer><strong>John Allspaw</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.kitchensoap.com/2012/10/25/on-being-a-senior-engineer/'>www.kitchensoap.com/2012/10/25/&hellip;</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p></p>

<p>Soon I&#8217;ll be able to write up some technical JS posts, and I&#8217;m starting to dig into <a href="http://www.golang.com">Go</a>. Are you doing interesting things with Go? If so, let me know about it!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[things i'm into lately]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/09/30/things-im-into-lately/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-30T17:13:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/09/30/things-im-into-lately</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>1) <a href="http://www.hovding.com/en/us/">hovding</a></p>

<p>This is an &#8220;invisible&#8221; bike helmet developed by two Swedish Industrial Designers, Anna Haupt and Terese Alstin.</p>

<p>2) <a href="http://soundcloud.com/harvard/changing-the-ratio-why-should">Changing the Ratio: Why Should You Care? - Rachel Sklar</a></p>

<p>Notable soundbite:</p>

<blockquote><p>Sklar warned against &#8220;pattern recognition,&#8221; which she described as a &#8220;preconceived idea of what a boss, an entrepreneur, an anchor or a president look like.&#8221; This can be a good thing, she noted, as it allows a person to &#8220;see areas in which positive things emerge,&#8221; but if a person&#8217;s preexisting notion is the only standard with which to view the world, that person is &#8220;shutting off opportunities for innovation across a multitude of other sectors.&#8221;</p><footer><strong>Janell Sims,</strong> <cite><a href='http://shorensteincenter.org/2012/09/speaker-series-with-rachel-sklar/'>shorensteincenter.org/2012/09/&hellip;</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>3) <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Snow-Crash-Bantam-Spectra-Book/dp/0553380958">Snow Crash</a></p>

<p>Snow Crash is Neal Stephenson&#8217;s third novel and is a story interweaving history, linguistics, anthropology, archaeology, religion, computer science, politics, cryptography, memetics, and philosophy. I&#8217;m totally enthralled by the two awesome protagonists Hiro Protagonist and Y.T.</p>

<p>4) <a href="http://open.spotify.com/user/trippg/playlist/5WnQHkFSqTPXTUi6WiKhav">Bluegrass Playlist on Spotify</a></p>

<p>Bluegrass (new and old) is just in my blood, guys. I can&#8217;t shake it, I don&#8217;t want to.</p>

<p>5) <a href="https://sphotos-b.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ash3/601447_10152121440770291_748201501_n.jpg">Making (and eating) this pecan pie</a></p>

<p>You may not have my secret recipe!</p>

<p>6) <a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/16029337/goldieblox-the-engineering-toy-for-girls">GoldieBlox, the Engineering toy for Girls</a></p>

<p>I backed GoldieBlox on KickStarter and I&#8217;m <em>very</em> impressed with Debbie Sterling.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[first nashville women's STEM group meetup]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/first-nashville-womens-stem-group-meetup/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-29T11:49:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/first-nashville-womens-stem-group-meetup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m happy to report the first Nashville Women&#8217;s STEM Group meet up was <em>a crazy amount of fun</em>. The highlights included conversations on skepticism, nuclear pharmacy, minecraft (complete with a demonstration), infectious diseases, and really intriguing discussions on our shared experiences as females in technical fields. It was really nice to have a few beers with so many funny, brilliant women.</p>

<h3>talking points for reflection</h3>

<blockquote><p>&#8220;I&#8217;m not asking for special treatment, but i&#8217;m not one of the guys. It&#8217;s not too much to ask for this consideration.&#8221;</p></blockquote>




<blockquote><p>&#8220;I&#8217;m not very girly, but I&#8217;ve had to act even more girly just to draw the line.&#8221;</p></blockquote>




<blockquote><p>&#8220;It&#8217;s never the fact that someone said something that one time, it&#8217;s always that one last time that pushes you over.&#8221;</p></blockquote>


<h3>Things I can&#8217;t stop loling over</h3>

<blockquote><p>&#8220;That sign says, &#8216;Our high gravity beer is out of this world&#8217;, I think we should ask them to change that&#8230;&#8221;</p></blockquote>




<blockquote><p>&#8220;The Committee for Skeptical Inquiry is having a conference in Nashville&#8230;I was doubtful they would ever come here.&#8221;</p></blockquote>


<h3>Next meeting</h3>

<p>Our next meeting is <strong>Nov 14th</strong>, most likely at 12th S Taproom. The interest I&#8217;ve seen from people who couldn&#8217;t make it last time is exciting. I&#8217;m also happy to announce we&#8217;re vetting sponsors, and some really fun events are coming our way in the new year!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[my actual response to the anonymous idiots on the internet]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/09/27/my-actual-response-to-the-anonymous-idiots-on-the-internet/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-27T13:16:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/09/27/my-actual-response-to-the-anonymous-idiots-on-the-internet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My previous post was a bit tongue in cheek, and honestly, it was just so absurd I couldn&#8217;t <a href="http://i.chzbgr.com/completestore/2012/3/8/eb9c0160-78f4-4f08-8a03-34bbdb39a54e.jpg">halp</a> myself but share it with you.</p>

<p>After some reflection this is my actual response. My response to the anonymous idiots? No, friend. This is my response to you. These are a few things I&#8217;d like you to remember if you find yourself in a similar situation as I did in the Coursera forums today.</p>

<blockquote><p>Don’t waste your energy trying to educate or change opinions; go over, under, through, and opinions will change organically when you’re the boss. Or they won’t. Who cares? Do your thing, and don’t care if they like it.”</p><footer><strong>Tina Fey</strong> <cite>Bossypants</cite></footer></blockquote>




<blockquote><p>“So, my unsolicited advice to women in the workplace is this. When faced with sexism, or ageism, or lookism, or even really aggressive Buddhism, ask yourself the following question: “Is this person in between me and what I want to do?” If the answer is no, ignore it and move on. Your energy is better used doing your work and outpacing people that way. Then, when you’re in charge, don’t hire the people who were jerky to you.”</p><footer><strong>Tina Fey</strong> <cite>Bossypants</cite></footer></blockquote>




<blockquote><p>The best thing you can possibly do with your life is to tackle the m!therf&$ing sh!* out of it.</p><footer><strong>Sugar</strong> <cite>therumpus.net</cite></footer></blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[help craft my response to an anonymous idiot on the internet]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/09/27/help-craft-my-response-to-an-anonymous-idiot-on-the-internet/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-27T11:20:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/09/27/help-craft-my-response-to-an-anonymous-idiot-on-the-internet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes you see an anonymous post on the Internet that makes you 1) spit out your coffee 2) weep silently for humanity 3) hold a kitten while you gain your composure 4) Ask your friends to help you write a hilarious response.</p>

<p>Leave the response you&#8217;d like me to give this person in the comments below.</p>

<p>Is this an exercise in futility? Most definitely. Does it temporarily make me feel better? Absolutely.</p>

<blockquote><p>All of this is completely irrelevant to the class! However, since some feel it’s necessary to call, “sorority girls,” “women” because referring to them as “girls” is disrespectful, and “all about power.” Let’s do a reality check and see if you, “professional women” actually deserve the respect you demand.</p><p>Homo Sapiens Sapiens are a dimorphic species that evolved each gender differently and complimentary to facilitate survival. That arrangement worked successfully for millions of years. Along comes our cooperate masters, who see women not only as a whole new group to whom they can sell their products, (Cigarettes initially) but a whole new potential workforce as well. So, they facilitated the “women’s” movement, and here we are decades later. What was the result? Organizations led by homosexual women, who pat themselves on their bra-burning backs for their accomplishments of getting a little closer to what they really want, which is to be male! Congratulations!</p><p>You also got a decrease in life expectancy, which is getting ever closer to the man’s. Generations of latchkey children growing up in empty homes without their mothers to guide and nurture them as nature designed YOU to do! You bought into the hyper-reality and left our most precious assets to be raised by strangers! Congratulations!</p><p>The consequence of this has been generations of children, who have little or no manners, can’t utter or write an intelligent sentence, have little sense of belonging to anything, and who are consequently no longer competitive in the world. Congratulations!</p><p>Did Dad take over the job of raising the children? Of course not! Women don’t want that either! At the end of the day it is still all the same evolved traits and mechanisms that drive you to find men who have good genes and are good providers and to look down your noses at men who don’t “hunt.” When a woman stays home, she is a mother and housewife. When a man stays home to raise the children he is a bum!</p><p>In the final analysis, you are all nothing more tools for our cooperate masters, who with the promise of power, manipulated you into denying the truth of what you actually are, and into to sacrificing our most precious assets, our children, and consequently our future!</p><p>Now, you girls deserve respect for what again?</p></blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[JavaScript operators]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/09/21/javascript-operators/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-21T10:27:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/09/21/javascript-operators</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been discovering little oddities in JS lately, and I think it&#8217;s worthwhile to know about them, so let&#8217;s take a look.</p>

<h3>bitwise operators</h3>

<p><a href="http://es5.github.com/#x11.7">Bitwise operators</a> treat operands (the values on either side of the operator) as a sequence of 32 bits (zeros and ones). These operators manipulate the values as binary representations and then return integers.</p>

<p><em>Left Shift Operator ( &lt;&lt; ):</em></p>

<pre><code>x &lt;&lt; y
</code></pre>

<p>Shifts the x to the left by y bits.</p>

<p>Did you know:</p>

<pre><code>x &lt;&lt; y
</code></pre>

<p>is [almost*] the same as</p>

<pre><code>x * Math.pow(2, y)
</code></pre>

<p>Example of usage:</p>

<pre><code>console.log(10 * Math.pow(2, 10)); // logs 10240
console.log(10 &lt;&lt; 10); // logs 10240
</code></pre>

<p>[*truncating happens!]</p>

<p><em>Right Shift Operator ( >> ):</em></p>

<pre><code>x &gt;&gt; y
</code></pre>

<p>Shifts the x to the right by y bits.</p>

<p>Example of usage: You can parse hexadecimal values to get RGB color values</p>

<pre><code>var hex = 'FFEFD5'; // papayawhip
var rgb = parseInt(hex, 16); // value: 16773077

var red   = (rgb &gt;&gt; 16) &amp; 0xFF; // value: 255 
var green = (rgb &gt;&gt; 8) &amp; 0xFF; // value: 239
var blue  = rgb &amp; 0xFF; // value 213
</code></pre>

<p>(there are other bitwise operators in the spec, I&#8217;m just highlighting those interesting me to me here).</p>

<p>Note: JavaScript numbers are technically stored in 64-bits, but are treated as 32 bit when bitwise operators are used.</p>

<p>Also Note: There are a lot of dirty things you can do with bitwise operators, and I do not suggest them. One interesting implementation could be to store boolean flag information, one integer could hold 32 flags!</p>

<h3>converting a string to an integer with + and -</h3>

<p>I definitely do not recommend this, but it&#8217;s worth knowing about in case of extreme debugging.</p>

<pre><code>var wat = +"7", 
    meep = -"7", 
    tinyKitten = +"tiniest of kittens";

console.log(wat); // logs 7
console.log(typeof wat); // logs "number"

console.log(meep); // logs -7
console.log(typeof meep); // logs "number"

console.log(tinyKitten); // logs NaN
console.log(typeof tinyKitten) // logs "number"
</code></pre>

<h3>difference between i++ and ++i (same for decrement)</h3>

<p>++i returns the value of i after being incremented</p>

<p>i++ returns the value of i before incrementing</p>

<pre><code>var i = 0, j = 0;

console.log(++i); // logs 1
console.log(i++); // logs 0
</code></pre>

<h3>! and type casting</h3>

<p>Did you know that the ! operator will cast the type of objects, etc. as boolean?</p>

<pre><code>var kitten = {}, 
    newKitten = !kitten, 
    newerKitten = !!kitten;

console.log(typeof kitten) // logs "object"
console.log(newKitten); // logs false
console.log(typeof newKitten); // logs "boolean"
console.log(newerKitten); // logs true
</code></pre>

<p>Remember the !! is not a new operator, it&#8217;s just the ! (negation) operator twice. It&#8217;s still interesting/strange to me that it would cast the type.</p>

<p>If this kind of thing is interesting to you, I highly recommend reading through the <a href="http://es5.github.com/#x11.4">docs</a> or <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/JavaScript/Reference/Operators/Bitwise_Operators">MDN&#8217;s nice bitwise summary</a>.</p>

<p>Also, I&#8217;d love if you&#8217;d leave your favorite lesser known JS features in the comments!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[pledge]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/09/19/pledge/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-19T16:41:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/09/19/pledge</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Most awesome thing I saw on the internet today:</p>

<blockquote><p>I, Lindy West, a shrill bitch, do hereby pledge to talk really really loud in meetings if I have something to say, even if dudes are talking louder and they don&#8217;t like me. I refuse to be a turtle—unless it is some really loud species of brave turtle with big ideas. I will not hold back just because I&#8217;m afraid of being called a loudmouth bitch (or a &#8220;trenchmouth loud ass,&#8221; which I was called the other day and as far as I can tell is some sort of pirate insult). Also, I will use the fuck out of the internet, because they can&#8217;t drown you out on the internet. The end. Amen or whatever.</p><footer><strong>Lindy West</strong> <cite><a href='http://jezebel.com/5944642/women-speak-75-less-when-theyre-surrounded-by-dudes-and-thats-bad'>Women Speak Drastically Less When They’re Surrounded by Dudes. And That’s Bad.</a></cite></footer></blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[self expression]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/09/14/self-expression/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-14T14:53:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/09/14/self-expression</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wrote a short piece for the lovely Poornima Vijayashanker at <a href="http://femgineer.com">Femgineer</a>, go and check it out if you&#8217;d like to read my thoughts on learning to program!</p>

<h3>Excerpt:</h3>

<blockquote><p>Software Engineering is incredibly rewarding, particularly when you get past the “I don’t understand anything” threshold. You start to see connections and understand the “why” of things and not just the “how.” That’s when you realize programming isn’t as hard as you thought. The most important part is that you stick with it (and it will be hard). You need to realize programming is not an elite club, it’s just most programmers today were lucky enough to be exposed to it at an early age.</p><footer><strong>Martha Kelly Girdler</strong> <cite><a href='http://femgineer.com/2012/09/software-engineering-another-form-of-self-expression/'>Software Engineering Another Form of Self Expression</a></cite></footer></blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[hacker school: day 90]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/08/28/hacker-school-day-90/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-28T11:52:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/08/28/hacker-school-day-90</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_luxhb5MLBY1r52j4go1_500.jpg" /></p>

<p>I&#8217;m sitting in a cafe in Brooklyn, exhausted, disoriented, and happy. I&#8217;m thinking to myself, &#8220;Holy (enter your own choice expletive here). I did it, I finished Hacker School.&#8221; I look back at my post recapping the first day and it&#8217;s clear the rules of Hacker School permeate our lives, <em>and it feels completely natural</em>. Several Hacker Schoolers have told me how strange the outside world feels now.</p>

<p>During my time at Hacker School I&#8217;ve built my own CSS preprocessor in JS and static site generator in Python. I&#8217;ve contributed to BPython. I built deployment scripts with Boto/Fabric. I built a CLI chat server with sockets. I built full applications with frameworks I hadn&#8217;t touched before (Backbone/Node/Django/etc), and <em>quickly</em>. I took a Stanford course on databases. I&#8217;m taking courses on Machine Learning now. There&#8217;s no way I&#8217;m stopping, and I wouldn&#8217;t have found this place without being inspired by my friends here.</p>

<p>Even more importantly, I learned how to believe in myself. I learned how to ask for help. I learned how to fight my own biases and those of the people around me.</p>

<h3>What I&#8217;ll miss most:</h3>

<ul>
<li>Every single person here</li>
<li>Weekly gender and race discussions</li>
<li>Having deeply nerdy conversations with women I admire</li>
<li>Karaoke nights</li>
<li><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/etsylabs/4622257286/">Eatsy</a></li>
<li>IRC silliness</li>
<li>Epic email threads</li>
</ul>


<p>One thing I know, we&#8217;ll bring the <a href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/06/04/hacker-school-day-one/">&#8220;rules&#8221; of Hacker School</a> with us wherever we go.</p>

<p>After Hacker School I&#8217;m headed back to Nashville, a place I dearly love. This feeling of &#8220;otherness&#8221; is creeping in as I integrate back into the developer community there. A recent and popular developer conference had <a href="http://nashville.coderfaire.com/schedule/">one female speaker</a>. A company known for its great developer culture looks <a href="https://www.facebook.com/DevelopWithPurpose">eerily homogenous</a>. I have a lot of work to do here, and Hacker School has given me the skill set to do it.</p>

<p>So now, 90 days later, we go back out into the real world, egos in check, building code of consequence, and destroying stereotypes.</p>

<p>Thanks Sonali, Dave, Alan, Nick, Tom</p>

<p>Never Graduate!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[rehabilitating-the-arrogant-engineer]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/08/19/rehabilitating-the-arrogant-engineer/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-19T15:36:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/08/19/rehabilitating-the-arrogant-engineer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Randy knew that learning to play in the sandbox with others—especially really smart people with different skill sets—drives innovation faster than someone trying to figure it out on their own, no matter how smart they are. But Randy also knew this wasn’t easy because many great engineers have serious deficiencies when it comes to working well with others. He knew because he was one of these people. He was a top engineer and had firsthand experience in both working through his interpersonal issues and working successfully in a team environment.</p><footer><strong>Scott Weiss</strong> <cite><a href='http://scott.a16z.com/2012/08/09/rehabilitating-the-arrogant-engineer/'>Rehabilitating the Arrogant Engineer</a></cite></footer></blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[front-end performance]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/08/11/front-end-performance/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-11T11:18:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/08/11/front-end-performance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>First, there is more potential for improvement in focusing on the frontend. If we were able to cut backend response times in half, the end user response time would decrease only 5–10% overall. If, instead, we reduce the frontend performance by half, we would reduce overall response times by 40-45%</p><footer><strong>Steve Souders</strong> <cite>High Performance Web Sites: Essential Knowledge for Front-End Engineers</cite></footer></blockquote>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating an EC2 instance with Fabric/Boto]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/08/09/creating-an-ec2-instance-with-fabric-slash-boto/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-09T11:44:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/08/09/creating-an-ec2-instance-with-fabric-slash-boto</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lately i&#8217;ve been learning about networking/HTTP/various inner workings of the internet, so I&#8217;ve been working with AWS. I would like to share a script with you that I wrote to spin up EC2 instances.</p>

<h3>What is EC2?</h3>

<p><a href="http://aws.amazon.com/ec2/">Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud</a> is a branch of AWS (Amazon Web Services) that allows you to rent virtual computers &#8220;in the cloud.&#8221; For our purposes, we would like to configure our EC2 instance as a web server (but the set up for that will come in a later tutorial). <em>Pro tip:</em> If you&#8217;re new to AWS you can use EC2 micro instances (a small amount of space, appropriate for personal applications) free for a year.</p>

<h3>What is Fabric?</h3>

<p><a href="http://docs.fabfile.org/en/1.4.3/index.html">Fabric</a> is a Python library for automating application deployment and other systems administration tasks. Fabric allows you to easily run your Python programs through quality control at regular intervals (Continuous Integration). I use fabric to run tests, automate my git workflow, and deploy applications to local or remote servers.</p>

<p>The functions you want to run with the <em>fab</em> command go in a separate file called fabfile.py.</p>

<p>The script I&#8217;ve outline below is executed by running:</p>

<pre><code>fab create_server 
</code></pre>

<p>in your console.</p>

<h3>What is Boto?</h3>

<p>Boto is a Python interface to the family of Amazon Web Services. In this article I&#8217;ll only be referencing the Boto EC2 API (although, I highly recommend reading the <a href="http://boto.cloudhackers.com/en/latest/index.html">boto docs</a>).</p>

<h3>Creating an Amazon EC2 instance with Fabric and Boto</h3>

<p>First you&#8217;ll need an <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/">AWS account</a>, your <a href="https://forums.aws.amazon.com/thread.jspa?threadID=49738aw">AWS access key and AWS secret key</a>, a <a href="http://docs.amazonwebservices.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/using-network-security.html">security group</a> defined, and a <a href="http://docs.amazonwebservices.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/generating-a-keypair.html">key_pair</a> generated.</p>

<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/3305297.js?file=boto-fab'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>from fabric.api import *
from fabric.colors import green as _green, yellow as _yellow
import boto
import boto.ec2
from config import *
import time

def create_server():
    &quot;&quot;&quot;
    Creates EC2 Instance
    &quot;&quot;&quot;
    print(_green(&quot;Started...&quot;))
    print(_yellow(&quot;...Creating EC2 instance...&quot;))
    
    conn = boto.ec2.connect_to_region('us-west-2', aws_access_key_id=ec2_key, aws_secret_access_key=ec2_secret)
    image = conn.get_all_images(ec2_amis)
    
    group = conn.get_all_security_groups(groupnames=['quicklaunch-2'])[0]
    group.authorize(ip_protocol='tcp', from_port='22', to_port='22', cidr_ip='0.0.0.0/0')
    group.authorize(ip_protocol='tcp', from_port='80', to_port='80', cidr_ip='0.0.0.0/0')
    
    reservation = image[0].run(1, 1, key_name=ec2_key_pair, security_groups=ec2_security,
        instance_type=ec2_instancetype)
    instance = reservation.instances[0]
    conn.create_tags([instance.id], {&quot;Name&quot;:config['INSTANCE_NAME_TAG']})

    while instance.state == u'pending':
        print(_yellow(&quot;Instance state: %s&quot; % instance.state))
        time.sleep(10)
        instance.update()

    print(_green(&quot;Instance state: %s&quot; % instance.state))
    print(_green(&quot;Public dns: %s&quot; % instance.public_dns_name))

    return instance.public_dns_name</code></pre></noscript></div>


<h3>What the what is going on here?</h3>

<p>Let&#8217;s go line by line!<br/>
<strong>line 1.</strong> Import fabric.api<br/>
<strong>line 2.</strong> Import yellow and green to use in the console (because I likes it)<br/>
<strong>line 3.</strong> Import boto<br/>
<strong>line 4.</strong> Import boto.ec2 API<br/>
<strong>line 5.</strong> Import a local config file with my AWS credentials and other bits of information I would like to keep private<br/>
<strong>line 6.</strong> Import the time module from the Python library (you&#8217;ll see the usage of this in the script later)<br/>
<strong>line 8.</strong> define the function that fabric will execute<br/>
<strong>line 12/13.</strong> Print out to the console that this process has started<br/>
<strong>line 15.</strong> create a connection object with a specific region we would like to connect</p>

<p><strong> PRO TIP TO REDUCE MUCH PAIN </strong></p>

<p>AWS products allow you to select <a href="http://docs.amazonwebservices.com/general/latest/gr/rande.html">specific regional endpoints</a> to reduce latency (latency just means &#8220;slowness&#8221; in the response of the service)</p>

<p>By default (although this is not specified) Boto will use the eastern family of endpoints. If you would like to connect to the default you can use the &#8216;connect_ec2&#8217; method:</p>

<pre><code>conn = boto.connect_ec2(ec2_key, ec2_secret)
</code></pre>

<p><strong> END PRO TIP </strong></p>

<p><strong>line 17.</strong> Select the image you would like to use on the virtual machine you are renting. I chose Ubuntu. (Note this could contain a list of multiple images you want to use/iterate over, my list just has one item)</p>

<p><strong> More about AMI (Amazon Machine Images): </strong> An image is just a snapshot of an Operating System (Windows, Linux, etc.) that you can put on a computer.</p>

<p><strong>line 19.</strong> The run method returns a Reservation object which represents a collection of instances started at the same time. We&#8217;re only starting one (for now). There are a number of arguments you can specify here, I&#8217;m specifying the min number of instances to start (1), max number of instances to start (1), the key_name I want to use (name of the keypair I generated), security group, and instance_type (t1.micro).</p>

<p><strong> More about Key Pairs: </strong>
Public AMI instances have no password so you need a public/private key pair to log in to them. The public name of your key pair is embedded into your instance allowing you to use the private key (the .pem file you downloaded) when you ssh into your machine.</p>

<p><strong>line 22.</strong> Get a reference to our specific instance object</p>

<p><strong>line 23.</strong> Create a tag on this instance. This is optional. If you are managing many instances in one account, tags are a great way to organize and reference your instances.</p>

<p><strong>line 24.</strong> While the image is being loaded on the virtual machine, update the user that this process is still running. Update the user every 10 seconds.</p>

<p><strong>line 29/30</strong> When the image is done installing update the user and display the public DNS name of this instance.</p>

<p>Now you can use the public DNS name to ssh into the machine:</p>

<pre><code>ssh -i path/to/key/myKey.pem ubuntu@my-ubuntu-public-ip.amazonaws.com 
</code></pre>

<p>(( coming up soon, i&#8217;ll write a boto/fab script to install the software necessary on this machine to run a django app  ))</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zoe Pablo: role model for women]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/08/01/zoe-pablo-role-model-for-young-women/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-01T09:23:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/08/01/zoe-pablo-role-model-for-young-women</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I found this article from Zoe Pablo, Olympic weight lifter, [ <a href="http://zoepablosmith.wordpress.com/2012/07/23/thanks-but-no-thanks/">article source</a> ] today and am so excited to share my favorite highlights with you. Women are marginalized by how they look and quite frankly <em>it&#8217;s complete bullshit.</em></p>

<blockquote><p>The obvious choice of slander when talking about female weightlifting is “how unfeminine, girls shouldn’t be strong or have muscles, this is wrong”. And maybe they’re right… in the Victorian era.</p><footer><strong>Zoe Pablo</strong> <cite>Thanks (but No Thanks…)</cite></footer></blockquote>




<blockquote><p>we don’t lift weights in order to look hot, especially for the likes of men like that. What makes them think that we even WANT them to find us attractive? If you do, thanks very much, we’re flattered. But if you don’t, why do you really need to voice this opinion in the first place, and what makes you think we actually give a toss that you, personally, do not find us attractive? What do you want us to do? Shall we stop weightlifting, amend our diet in order to completely get rid of our ‘manly’ muscles, and become housewives in the sheer hope that one day you will look more favourably upon us and we might actually have a shot with you?!</p><footer><strong>Zoe Pablo</strong> <cite>Thanks (but No Thanks…)</cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>xoxo</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[interesting use case for recursion]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/07/02/interesting-use-case-for-recursion/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-02T21:53:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/07/02/interesting-use-case-for-recursion</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recursion is the process of defining an infinite set of objects by a single process. In programming an example of this is invoking a function from within itself.</p>

<p>I found an interesting use case for this when I was building my lightweight CSS pre-processor, <a href="https://github.com/marthakelly/bareBones.js">bareBones.js</a>, with JavaScript.</p>

<p>In bareBones I &#8220;tokenize&#8221; and format my custom CSS syntax into an array of objects representing CSS blocks. Each object could potentially have a children array of identically structured objects (re: data-structure gist).</p>

<p>To account for an infinite number of nested CSS objects I map the blockToCSS function over each object in the data array <em>and each object in its children array.</em> (recursion!)</p>

<p>If the object has no children the function will simply return a string of formatted CSS as a single entry in an array.</p>

<p>If the object has children it will map the same function over each object in the children array. (After that I reduce this array of arrays into an array of strings&#8230;a bit unorthodox, yes&#8230;:D).</p>

<p>Next, I map over each entry in this new array so I can concatenate the parent selector in front of each child to conserve CSS precedence.</p>

<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/3037040.js?file=data-structure.js'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;
&lt;html&gt;
  &lt;head prefix=&quot;og: http://ogp.me/ns# fb: http://ogp.me/ns/fb# githubog: http://ogp.me/ns/fb/githubog#&quot;&gt;
    &lt;meta charset='utf-8'&gt;
    &lt;meta http-equiv=&quot;X-UA-Compatible&quot; content=&quot;IE=edge&quot;&gt;
        &lt;title&gt;404 · GitHub&lt;/title&gt;
    &lt;link rel=&quot;search&quot; type=&quot;application/opensearchdescription+xml&quot; href=&quot;/opensearch.xml&quot; title=&quot;GitHub&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;link rel=&quot;fluid-icon&quot; href=&quot;https://raw.github.com/fluidicon.png&quot; title=&quot;GitHub&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;link rel=&quot;shortcut icon&quot; href=&quot;/favicon.ico&quot; type=&quot;image/x-icon&quot; /&gt;

    
    

    

    &lt;link href=&quot;https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/assets/github-821a01f5a1064ca5b91ff37b9cd308329a4db809.css&quot; media=&quot;screen&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;link href=&quot;https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/assets/github2-91c5df300a701cbdbfe4983871a12b00c13c4a23.css&quot; media=&quot;screen&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; /&gt;
    
    


    &lt;script src=&quot;https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/assets/frameworks-d27ba5bf5cfb627404b4314c54b0d85e1a3d889c.js&quot; type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    
    &lt;script defer=&quot;defer&quot; src=&quot;https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/assets/github-cdbee4200a2c75f2e6c49a1f1ea53fbd725139b4.js&quot; type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    
    

    
  &lt;/head&gt;


  &lt;body class=&quot;logged_out    env-production &quot; data-blob-contribs-enabled=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;wrapper&quot;&gt;

    
    
    

      &lt;div id=&quot;header&quot; class=&quot;true clearfix&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;container clearfix&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a class=&quot;site-logo&quot; href=&quot;https://raw.github.com/&quot;&gt;
            &lt;!--[if IE]&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&quot;GitHub&quot; class=&quot;github-logo&quot; src=&quot;https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov7.png?1323882716&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&quot;GitHub&quot; class=&quot;github-logo-hover&quot; src=&quot;https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov7-hover.png?1324325358&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;![endif]--&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&quot;GitHub&quot; class=&quot;github-logo-4x&quot; height=&quot;30&quot; src=&quot;https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov7@4x.png?1337118071&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;img alt=&quot;GitHub&quot; class=&quot;github-logo-4x-hover&quot; height=&quot;30&quot; src=&quot;https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov7@4x-hover.png?1337118071&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/a&gt;


                  &lt;!--
      make sure to use fully qualified URLs here since this nav
      is used on error pages on other domains
    --&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&quot;top-nav logged_out&quot;&gt;
        &lt;li class=&quot;pricing&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/plans&quot;&gt;Signup and Pricing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li class=&quot;explore&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/explore&quot;&gt;Explore GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;features&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/features&quot;&gt;Features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li class=&quot;blog&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/blog&quot;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li class=&quot;login&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/login?return_to=%2Fgist%2F3037040%2Fdata-structure.js&quot;&gt;Login&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;



          
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

      

        &lt;div class=&quot;site clearfix&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div id=&quot;site-container&quot; class=&quot;container&quot; data-pjax-container&gt;
            

&lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot;&gt;
    #header{
        border-bottom: 0;
    }
    .site {
        padding: 0;
    }
    #site-container {
        width: 100%;
    }
    * {
        margin: 0px;
        padding: 0px;
    }
    #parallax_wrapper {
      position: relative;
      z-index: 0;
    }
    #parallax_field{
        overflow: hidden;
        position: absolute;
        left: 0;
        top: 0;
        height: 370px;
        width: 100%;
    }
    #parallax_field #parallax_bg {
        position: absolute;
        top: -20px;
        left: -20px;
        width: 110%;
        height: 425px;
        z-index: 1;
    }
    #parallax_illustration {
        display: block;
        margin: 0 auto;
        width: 940px;
        height: 370px;
        position: relative;
        overflow: hidden;
        clear: both;
    }
    #parallax_illustration #parallax_error_text {
        position: absolute;
        top: 72px;
        left: 72px;
        z-index: 10;
    }
    #parallax_illustration #parallax_octocat {
        position: absolute;
        top: 94px;
        left: 356px;
        z-index: 9;
    }
    #parallax_illustration #parallax_speeder {
        position: absolute;
        top: 150px;
        left: 432px;
        z-index: 8;
    }
    #parallax_illustration #parallax_octocatshadow {
        position: absolute;
        top: 297px;
        left: 371px;
        z-index: 7;
    }
    #parallax_illustration #parallax_speedershadow {
        position: absolute;
        top: 263px;
        left: 442px;
        z-index: 6;
    }
    #parallax_illustration #parallax_building_1 {
        position: absolute;
        top: 73px;
        left: 467px;
        z-index: 5;
    }
    #parallax_illustration #parallax_building_2 {
        position: absolute;
        top: 113px;
        left: 762px;
        z-index: 4;
    }
    #footer-push {
      height: 280px;
    }
    #footer {
        margin-top: 0px;
        z-index: 12;
    }
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;parallax_wrapper&quot;&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;parallax_field&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&quot;building&quot; class=&quot;js-plaxify&quot; data-invert=&quot;true&quot; data-xrange=&quot;0&quot; data-yrange=&quot;20&quot; height=&quot;415&quot; id=&quot;parallax_bg&quot; src=&quot;https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/404/parallax_bg.jpg?1315867479&quot; width=&quot;940&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;parallax_illustration&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;404 | &amp;ldquo;This is not the web page you are looking for&amp;rdquo;&quot; class=&quot;js-plaxify&quot; data-xrange=&quot;20&quot; data-yrange=&quot;10&quot; height=&quot;249&quot; id=&quot;parallax_error_text&quot; src=&quot;https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/404/parallax_errortext.png?1315867479&quot; width=&quot;271&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Octobi Wan Catnobi&quot; class=&quot;js-plaxify&quot; data-xrange=&quot;10&quot; data-yrange=&quot;10&quot; height=&quot;230&quot; id=&quot;parallax_octocat&quot; src=&quot;https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/404/parallax_octocat.png?1315867479&quot; width=&quot;188&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;land speeder&quot; class=&quot;js-plaxify&quot; data-xrange=&quot;10&quot; data-yrange=&quot;10&quot; height=&quot;156&quot; id=&quot;parallax_speeder&quot; src=&quot;https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/404/parallax_speeder.png?1315867479&quot; width=&quot;440&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;Octobi Wan Catnobi's shadow&quot; class=&quot;js-plaxify&quot; data-xrange=&quot;10&quot; data-yrange=&quot;10&quot; height=&quot;49&quot; id=&quot;parallax_octocatshadow&quot; src=&quot;https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/404/parallax_octocatshadow.png?1315867479&quot; width=&quot;166&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;land speeder's shadow&quot; class=&quot;js-plaxify&quot; data-xrange=&quot;10&quot; data-yrange=&quot;10&quot; height=&quot;75&quot; id=&quot;parallax_speedershadow&quot; src=&quot;https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/404/parallax_speedershadow.png?1315867479&quot; width=&quot;430&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;building&quot; class=&quot;js-plaxify&quot; data-invert=&quot;true&quot; data-xrange=&quot;50&quot; data-yrange=&quot;20&quot; height=&quot;123&quot; id=&quot;parallax_building_1&quot; src=&quot;https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/404/parallax_building_1.png?1315867479&quot; width=&quot;304&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;img alt=&quot;building&quot; class=&quot;js-plaxify&quot; data-invert=&quot;true&quot; data-xrange=&quot;75&quot; data-yrange=&quot;30&quot; height=&quot;50&quot; id=&quot;parallax_building_2&quot; src=&quot;https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/404/parallax_building_2.png?1315867479&quot; width=&quot;116&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

          &lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;context-overlay&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div id=&quot;footer-push&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- hack for sticky footer --&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- end of wrapper - hack for sticky footer --&gt;

      &lt;!-- footer --&gt;
      &lt;div id=&quot;footer&quot; &gt;
        
  &lt;div class=&quot;upper_footer&quot;&gt;
     &lt;div class=&quot;container clearfix&quot;&gt;

       &lt;!--[if IE]&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;blacktocat_ie&quot;&gt;GitHub Links&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;![endif]--&gt;
       &lt;![if !IE]&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;blacktocat&quot;&gt;GitHub Links&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;![endif]&gt;

       &lt;ul class=&quot;footer_nav&quot;&gt;
         &lt;h4&gt;GitHub&lt;/h4&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/about&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/blog&quot;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/features&quot;&gt;Features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/contact&quot;&gt;Contact &amp;amp; Support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/training&quot;&gt;Training&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://enterprise.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Enterprise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://status.github.com/&quot;&gt;Site Status&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;/ul&gt;

       &lt;ul class=&quot;footer_nav&quot;&gt;
         &lt;h4&gt;Tools&lt;/h4&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://get.gaug.es/&quot;&gt;Gauges: Analyze web traffic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://speakerdeck.com&quot;&gt;Speaker Deck: Presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com&quot;&gt;Gist: Code snippets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mac.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub for Mac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://windows.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub for Windows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mobile.github.com/&quot;&gt;Issues for iPhone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jobs.github.com/&quot;&gt;Job Board&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;/ul&gt;

       &lt;ul class=&quot;footer_nav&quot;&gt;
         &lt;h4&gt;Extras&lt;/h4&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://shop.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Shop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://octodex.github.com/&quot;&gt;The Octodex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;/ul&gt;

       &lt;ul class=&quot;footer_nav&quot;&gt;
         &lt;h4&gt;Documentation&lt;/h4&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://help.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://developer.github.com/&quot;&gt;Developer API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://github.github.com/github-flavored-markdown/&quot;&gt;GitHub Flavored Markdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;/ul&gt;

     &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- /.site --&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- /.upper_footer --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;lower_footer&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;container clearfix&quot;&gt;
    &lt;!--[if IE]&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;legal_ie&quot;&gt;&lt;![endif]--&gt;
    &lt;![if !IE]&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;legal&quot;&gt;&lt;![endif]&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/site/terms&quot;&gt;Terms of Service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/site/privacy&quot;&gt;Privacy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;&amp;copy; 2012 &lt;span title=&quot;0.02052s from fe9.rs.github.com&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt; Inc. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- /#legal or /#legal_ie--&gt;

      &lt;div class=&quot;sponsor&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rackspace.com&quot; class=&quot;logo&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img alt=&quot;Dedicated Server&quot; height=&quot;36&quot; src=&quot;https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/footer/rackspaces_logo.png?1329521039&quot; width=&quot;38&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
        Powered by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rackspace.com &quot;&gt;Dedicated
        Servers&lt;/a&gt; and&lt;br/&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rackspacecloud.com&quot;&gt;Cloud
        Computing&lt;/a&gt; of Rackspace Hosting&lt;span&gt;&amp;reg;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- /.site --&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- /.lower_footer --&gt;

      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- /#footer --&gt;

    

&lt;div id=&quot;keyboard_shortcuts_pane&quot; class=&quot;instapaper_ignore readability-extra&quot; style=&quot;display:none&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Keyboard Shortcuts &lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; class=&quot;js-see-all-keyboard-shortcuts&quot;&gt;(see all)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;columns threecols&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;column first&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h3&gt;Site wide shortcuts&lt;/h3&gt;
      &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt&gt;s&lt;/dt&gt;
        &lt;dd&gt;Focus site search&lt;/dd&gt;
      &lt;/dl&gt;
      &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt&gt;?&lt;/dt&gt;
        &lt;dd&gt;Bring up this help dialog&lt;/dd&gt;
      &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- /.column.first --&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;column middle&quot; style='display:none'&gt;
      &lt;h3&gt;Commit list&lt;/h3&gt;
      &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt&gt;j&lt;/dt&gt;
        &lt;dd&gt;Move selection down&lt;/dd&gt;
      &lt;/dl&gt;
      &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt&gt;k&lt;/dt&gt;
        &lt;dd&gt;Move selection up&lt;/dd&gt;
      &lt;/dl&gt;
      &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt&gt;c &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; o &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; enter&lt;/dt&gt;
        &lt;dd&gt;Open commit&lt;/dd&gt;
      &lt;/dl&gt;
      &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt&gt;y&lt;/dt&gt;
        &lt;dd&gt;Expand URL to its canonical form&lt;/dd&gt;
      &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- /.column.first --&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;column last&quot; style='display:none'&gt;
      &lt;h3&gt;Pull request list&lt;/h3&gt;
      &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt&gt;j&lt;/dt&gt;
        &lt;dd&gt;Move selection down&lt;/dd&gt;
      &lt;/dl&gt;
      &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt&gt;k&lt;/dt&gt;
        &lt;dd&gt;Move selection up&lt;/dd&gt;
      &lt;/dl&gt;
      &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt&gt;o &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; enter&lt;/dt&gt;
        &lt;dd&gt;Open issue&lt;/dd&gt;
      &lt;/dl&gt;
      &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;platform-mac&quot;&gt;⌘&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;platform-other&quot;&gt;ctrl&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;+&lt;/em&gt; enter&lt;/dt&gt;
        &lt;dd&gt;Submit comment&lt;/dd&gt;
      &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- /.columns.last --&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- /.columns.equacols --&gt;

  &lt;div style='display:none'&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;h3&gt;Issues&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;columns threecols&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;column first&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;j&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Move selection down&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;k&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Move selection up&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;x&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Toggle selection&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;o &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; enter&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Open issue&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;platform-mac&quot;&gt;⌘&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;platform-other&quot;&gt;ctrl&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;+&lt;/em&gt; enter&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Submit comment&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- /.column.first --&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;column last&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;c&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Create issue&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;l&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Create label&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;i&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Back to inbox&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;u&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Back to issues&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;/&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Focus issues search&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div style='display:none'&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;h3&gt;Issues Dashboard&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;columns threecols&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;column first&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;j&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Move selection down&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;k&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Move selection up&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;o &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; enter&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Open issue&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- /.column.first --&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div style='display:none'&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;h3&gt;Network Graph&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;columns equacols&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;column first&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;badmono&quot;&gt;←&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; h&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Scroll left&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;badmono&quot;&gt;→&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; l&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Scroll right&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;badmono&quot;&gt;↑&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; k&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Scroll up&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;badmono&quot;&gt;↓&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; j&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Scroll down&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;t&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Toggle visibility of head labels&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- /.column.first --&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;column last&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;shift &lt;span class=&quot;badmono&quot;&gt;←&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; shift h&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Scroll all the way left&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;shift &lt;span class=&quot;badmono&quot;&gt;→&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; shift l&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Scroll all the way right&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;shift &lt;span class=&quot;badmono&quot;&gt;↑&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; shift k&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Scroll all the way up&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;shift &lt;span class=&quot;badmono&quot;&gt;↓&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; shift j&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Scroll all the way down&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- /.column.last --&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div style='display:none'&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;columns threecols&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;column first&quot; style='display:none'&gt;
        &lt;h3&gt;Source Code Browsing&lt;/h3&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;t&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Activates the file finder&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;l&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Jump to line&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;w&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Switch branch/tag&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;y&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Expand URL to its canonical form&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div style='display:none'&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;columns threecols&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;column first&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h3&gt;Browsing Commits&lt;/h3&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;platform-mac&quot;&gt;⌘&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;platform-other&quot;&gt;ctrl&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;+&lt;/em&gt; enter&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Submit comment&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;escape&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Close form&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;p&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Parent commit&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
        &lt;dl class=&quot;keyboard-mappings&quot;&gt;
          &lt;dt&gt;o&lt;/dt&gt;
          &lt;dd&gt;Other parent commit&lt;/dd&gt;
        &lt;/dl&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;div id=&quot;markdown-help&quot; class=&quot;instapaper_ignore readability-extra&quot;&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;Markdown Cheat Sheet&lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;cheatsheet-content&quot;&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;mod&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h3&gt;Format Text&lt;/h3&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Headers&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;pre&gt;
# This is an &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt; tag
## This is an &amp;lt;h2&amp;gt; tag
###### This is an &amp;lt;h6&amp;gt; tag&lt;/pre&gt;
     &lt;p&gt;Text styles&lt;/p&gt;
     &lt;pre&gt;
*This text will be italic*
_This will also be italic_
**This text will be bold**
__This will also be bold__

*You **can** combine them*
&lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h3&gt;Lists&lt;/h3&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Unordered&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;pre&gt;
* Item 1
* Item 2
  * Item 2a
  * Item 2b&lt;/pre&gt;
     &lt;p&gt;Ordered&lt;/p&gt;
     &lt;pre&gt;
1. Item 1
2. Item 2
3. Item 3
   * Item 3a
   * Item 3b&lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h3&gt;Miscellaneous&lt;/h3&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Images&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;pre&gt;
![GitHub Logo](/images/logo.png)
Format: ![Alt Text](url)
&lt;/pre&gt;
     &lt;p&gt;Links&lt;/p&gt;
     &lt;pre&gt;
http://github.com - automatic!
[GitHub](http://github.com)&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blockquotes&lt;/p&gt;
     &lt;pre&gt;
As Kanye West said:

&gt; We're living the future so
&gt; the present is our past.
&lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;rule&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;h3&gt;Code Examples in Markdown&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Syntax highlighting with &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.github.com/github-flavored-markdown/&quot; title=&quot;GitHub Flavored Markdown&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GFM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;pre&gt;
```javascript
function fancyAlert(arg) {
  if(arg) {
    $.facebox({div:'#foo'})
  }
}
```&lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Or, indent your code 4 spaces&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;pre&gt;
Here is a Python code example
without syntax highlighting:

    def foo:
      if not bar:
        return true&lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Inline code for comments&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;pre&gt;
I think you should use an
`&amp;lt;addr&amp;gt;` element here instead.&lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


    &lt;div id=&quot;ajax-error-message&quot;&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;mini-icon mini-icon-exclamation&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
      Something went wrong with that request. Please try again.
      &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; class=&quot;ajax-error-dismiss&quot;&gt;Dismiss&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;div id=&quot;logo-popup&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h2&gt;Looking for the GitHub logo?&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          &lt;h4&gt;GitHub Logo&lt;/h4&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://github-media-downloads.s3.amazonaws.com/GitHub_Logos.zip&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Github_logo&quot; src=&quot;https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/about_page/github_logo.png?1315867479&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://github-media-downloads.s3.amazonaws.com/GitHub_Logos.zip&quot; class=&quot;minibutton btn-download download&quot;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
          &lt;h4&gt;The Octocat&lt;/h4&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://github-media-downloads.s3.amazonaws.com/Octocats.zip&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Octocat&quot; src=&quot;https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/about_page/octocat.png?1315867479&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://github-media-downloads.s3.amazonaws.com/Octocats.zip&quot; class=&quot;minibutton btn-download download&quot;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    
    
    
    &lt;span id='server_response_time' data-time='0.02889' data-host='fe9'&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;
</code></pre></noscript></div>


<p>The rest of this function (and the program) involves formatting the CSS which is not particularly interesting for a recursion discussion. Contact me if you want to know more!</p>

<p>Hopefully this gives you more insight into use cases where recursion could be useful, especially with nested data structures!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unlocking the Clubhouse]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/06/26/unlocking-the-clubhouse/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-26T08:47:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/06/26/unlocking-the-clubhouse</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>The goal is not to fit women into computer science as it is currently taught and conceived. Rather, a cultural and curricular revolution is required.</p><footer><strong>Jane Margolis, Allan Fisher</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.amazon.com/Unlocking-Clubhouse-Computing-Jane-Margolis/dp/0262133989'>www.amazon.com/dp/0262133989/&hellip;</a></cite></footer></blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
