<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Martha Kelly]]></title>
  <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-25T12:09:04-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Martha Kelly]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[daily inspiration]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/05/25/daily-inspiration/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-25T11:58:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/05/25/daily-inspiration</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>As one of the few female students studying automotive design, I naively felt the need to blend in with my male classmates and find a way to minimize being seen as the only girl. I contemplated signing all of my design sketches as “Chris Park” instead of “Christine Park,” but in the back of my mind I knew it didn’t feel right. My professor offered some great guidance by telling me, “Be who you are.” I learned to embrace the fact that my uniqueness helped set me apart.</p></blockquote>




<blockquote><p>Today, working in an industry where there are few women, I can bring a different perspective to the table. But, I never want my gender to define me. Instead, my work will speak for itself, and I now know the key is being comfortable in my own skin.</p></blockquote>


<p>Christine Park - <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/jennagoudreau/2012/05/25/how-i-went-from-art-school-to-gms-senior-cadillac-designer-by-age-28/">How I Went From Art School To GM&#8217;s Senior Cadillac Designer By Age 28</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[hello internet]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/05/21/hello-internet/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-21T18:30:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/05/21/hello-internet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi, I&#8217;m Martha. I&#8217;m a developer for Cheezburger Network (I Can Has Cheezburger, Failblog, Memebase, Know Your Meme). Well, at least I will be until June. I&#8217;m really excited to announce that I&#8217;ve been accepted into the summer batch of <a href="http://www.hackerschool.com">Hacker School</a> hosted at <a href="http://www.etsy.com">Etsy</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>Hacker School is a three-month, full-time school in New York for becoming a better programmer. We&#8217;re free as in beer, and provide space, a little structure, time to focus, and a friendly community of smart builders dedicated to self-improvement.</p></blockquote>


<p>I&#8217;ll spend my summer crunching code in the amazing <a href="http://mashable.com/2010/10/13/etsy-office-pics/#view_as_one_page-gallery_box377">Etsy offices in Brooklyn</a>. Their goal is to make me &#8220;a significantly better programmer.&#8221;</p>

<p>My goal is to exceed their expectations.</p>

<p>Never graduate! <br />
Martha</p>

<p>p.s.
blog design was hastily put together (I used <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a>) - it will probably change constantly :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
