<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Martha Kelly]]></title>
  <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-06-13T08:12:21-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Martha Kelly]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[creator vs builder]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/06/13/creator-vs-builder/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-13T07:59:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/06/13/creator-vs-builder</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>And here’s the real crux of the problem: software engineers aren’t builders. Software engineers are creators. Building is what you do when you buy a piece of furniture from Ikea and get it home. The instructions are laid out and if you go step by step, you’ll get that comically small table you wanted. Creating is a different process, it’s birthing something without direction or instruction. It’s starting with a blank canvas and painting a masterpiece. Software engineers don’t get into coding because they want someone to tell them what to do, they get into it because they discovered they could create something useful. Every single software engineer fell in love with coding because she made a small, useful program early on and was hooked.</p></blockquote>


<p><a href="http://www.nczonline.net/blog/2012/06/12/the-care-and-feeding-of-software-engineers-or-why-engineers-are-grumpy/">The care and feeding of software engineers (or, why engineers are grumpy)</a> - Nicholas C. Zakas</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[hacker school: day one]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/06/04/hacker-school-day-one/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-04T21:39:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/06/04/hacker-school-day-one</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://distilleryimage3.instagram.com/cb3e5f00aeb411e1a9f71231382044a1_7.jpg" /></p>

<p>The people here are <em>phenomenal</em>. I never realized the impact of being the only female in the room until I wasn&#8217;t. Every person here is smart, interesting, funny, supportive, capable, and very different from one another. The skill sets vary from designer, web developer, pastry chef, functional programmer, physics postdoc, astrophysicist, financial analyst, CS student, hardware engineer, etc, etc. I&#8217;m inspired by all of them.</p>

<h2>We have rules at Hacker School</h2>

<blockquote><p>The few rules we do have are social and aim to fix some of the bugs we&#8217;ve found in other communities. Social conventions govern most of the world, but they&#8217;re usually unspoken. We make some social rules explicit at Hacker School because we&#8217;ve found it makes for a better environment.</p></blockquote>


<p><a href="https://www.hackerschool.com/blog/1-summer-2012-applications-open">source</a></p>

<h3>1) no saying &#8220;well actually&#8221;</h3>

<p>When you engage in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parkinson's_Law_of_Triviality">bikeshedding</a> you discourage people from asking questions and learning. Are you trying to help, or just showing off? Instead, let the conversation take its course. If it&#8217;s a critical issue you can address it when you pair program with that person.</p>

<h3>2) no feigning surprise</h3>

<p><em>&#8220;You mean you don&#8217;t know who Richard Stallman is??&#8221;</em> is not helpful :) Instead share knowledge openly. There is no shame in not knowing something, it just means you haven&#8217;t encountered it yet.</p>

<h3>3) no backseat driving</h3>

<p>Jumping in at the tail end of a conversation to interject your opinion is distracting and could prevent your colleagues from learning on their own. Instead ask if they would like you to join the conversation.</p>

<h3>4) no subtle sexism, racism, or any discrimination</h3>

<p>Being offended is a very subjective experience, but if you make any person feel uncomfortable and they address it with you, <em>apologize</em>.</p>

<h2>how to get the most out of hacker school</h2>

<h3>1) Open the box</h3>

<p>Study the source code of the libraries and applications you use. If you work with a tool and it &#8220;magically&#8221; works - uncover that magic.</p>

<h3>2) know that great programmers have no ego and nothing to prove.</h3>

<p>Great programmers acknowledge how little they know in the grand scheme of things. They have nothing to prove and are totally secure in their own abilities.</p>

<h3>3) If something looks hard it&#8217;s probably because you&#8217;ve never seen it before.</h3>

<p>You learn faster than you give yourself credit for so challenge yourself. Dive into something crazy, you have the support of everyone here.</p>

<h3>4) Never take on a project where you won&#8217;t learn something new.</h3>

<p>If you&#8217;re not learning something new you&#8217;re only repeating something you already knew. Learn constantly.</p>

<h3>5) Build code of consequence</h3>

<p>You should write code that other developers will use all the time. Contribute to open source projects you care about and build tools other developers will use.</p>

<p>Honestly, this is all applicable to <em>your</em> life. Can you imagine STEM being a diverse and supportive community building amazing things together? I can :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linda Liukas - What every girl needs to know about programming]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/05/30/what-every-girl-needs-to-know-about-programming/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-30T12:57:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/05/30/what-every-girl-needs-to-know-about-programming</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe width="640" height="510" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/_rkkFdQeBlA " frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p></p>

<h3>Highlights:</h3>

<ul>
<li>The low number of girls and women in programming is a systematic problem, something fundamental is missing</li>
<li>Teenage girls have a massive amount of crazy and creative energy, they <em>should</em> learn to code</li>
<li>Coding is not lonely and it&#8217;s not mathematical</li>
<li>We are so stuck in semantics and exclusion that we can&#8217;t function as a community, it&#8217;s no longer fun and enjoyable</li>
<li>It&#8217;s up to us to create a new culture of development - one that is fun and focuses on creating and building</li>
</ul>


<h3>My thoughts:</h3>

<p>Linda Liukas <em>thank you, thank you, thank you</em>.</p>

<p>Right now (in technology) girls are rewarded when they fit in with the boys, but what about the girls that don&#8217;t and just want to be <em>themselves</em>? The outlets for them are few and far between.</p>

<h3>Not convinced? Try thinking about it this way:</h3>

<p>There are many girls and women frustrated by their experiences in programming, but men are not equally as frustrated. There are few girls and women pursing technology, but there is an abundance of white males. <em>This means it&#8217;s not the same situation</em>. There&#8217;s no reason at all that girls (and boys for that matter!) who like shoes, nail polish, and miu miu handbags can&#8217;t build amazing products that get just as much recognition.</p>

<h3>What can we do to help?</h3>

<p>Girls need more inclusion and more role models (how many female Mark Zuckerbergs can you think of?). Support organizations that make building and learning about technology fun (for example, <a href="http://railsgirls.com/">Rails Girls</a>). This should go without saying, but you should end any RTFM shaming, sexual/objectifying images, and demeaning jokes in the tech communities and workplaces you&#8217;re a part of.</p>

<blockquote><p>If I should ever have a daughter or a son I would like them to see the world of technology through this lens of magical culture.</p><footer><strong>Linda Liukas</strong> <cite>What Every Girl Needs to Know About Programming</cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>Please check out <a href="http://railsgirls.com/">Rails Girls</a>, and Linda - thank you.</p>

<p>(also, check out <a href="http://www.lindaliukas.fi/">Linda&#8217;s website!</a>)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[inspired]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/05/25/daily-inspiration/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-25T11:58:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/05/25/daily-inspiration</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>As one of the few female students studying automotive design, I naively felt the need to blend in with my male classmates and find a way to minimize being seen as the only girl. I contemplated signing all of my design sketches as “Chris Park” instead of “Christine Park,” but in the back of my mind I knew it didn’t feel right. My professor offered some great guidance by telling me, “Be who you are.” I learned to embrace the fact that my uniqueness helped set me apart.</p></blockquote>




<blockquote><p>Today, working in an industry where there are few women, I can bring a different perspective to the table. But, I never want my gender to define me. Instead, my work will speak for itself, and I now know the key is being comfortable in my own skin.</p></blockquote>


<p>Christine Park - <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/jennagoudreau/2012/05/25/how-i-went-from-art-school-to-gms-senior-cadillac-designer-by-age-28/">How I Went From Art School To GM&#8217;s Senior Cadillac Designer By Age 28</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[hello internet]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/05/21/hello-internet/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-21T18:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/05/21/hello-internet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi, I&#8217;m Martha. I&#8217;m a developer for Cheezburger Network (I Can Has Cheezburger, Failblog, Memebase, Know Your Meme). Well, at least I will be until June. I&#8217;m really excited to announce that I&#8217;ve been accepted into the summer batch of <a href="http://www.hackerschool.com">Hacker School</a> hosted at <a href="http://www.etsy.com">Etsy</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>Hacker School is a three-month, full-time school in New York for becoming a better programmer. We&#8217;re free as in beer, and provide space, a little structure, time to focus, and a friendly community of smart builders dedicated to self-improvement.</p></blockquote>


<p>I&#8217;ll spend my summer crunching code in the amazing <a href="http://mashable.com/2010/10/13/etsy-office-pics/#view_as_one_page-gallery_box377">Etsy offices in Brooklyn</a>. Their goal is to make me &#8220;a significantly better programmer.&#8221;</p>

<p>My goal is to exceed their expectations.</p>

<p>Never graduate! <br />
Martha</p>

<p>p.s.
blog design was hastily put together (I used <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a>) - it will change constantly :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
