<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: nashSTEM | Martha Kelly]]></title>
  <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/categories/nashstem/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-21T21:18:52-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Martha Kelly]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[first nashville women's STEM group meetup]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/first-nashville-womens-stem-group-meetup/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-29T11:49:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/first-nashville-womens-stem-group-meetup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm happy to report the first Nashville Women's STEM Group meet up was <em>a crazy amount of fun</em>. The highlights included conversations on skepticism, nuclear pharmacy, minecraft (complete with a demonstration), infectious diseases, and really intriguing discussions on our shared experiences as females in technical fields. It was really nice to have a few beers with so many funny, brilliant women.</p>

<h3>talking points for reflection</h3>

<p><blockquote><p>"I'm not asking for special treatment, but i'm not one of the guys. It's not too much to ask for this consideration."</p></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>"I'm not very girly, but I've had to act even more girly just to draw the line."</p></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>"It's never the fact that someone said something that one time, it's always that one last time that pushes you over."</p></blockquote></p>

<h3>Things I can't stop loling over</h3>

<p><blockquote><p>"That sign says, 'Our high gravity beer is out of this world', I think we should ask them to change that..."</p></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>"The Committee for Skeptical Inquiry is having a conference in Nashville...I was doubtful they would ever come here."</p></blockquote></p>

<h3>Next meeting</h3>

<p>Our next meeting is <strong>Nov 14th</strong>, most likely at 12th S Taproom. The interest I've seen from people who couldn't make it last time is exciting. I'm also happy to announce we're vetting sponsors, and some really fun events are coming our way in the new year!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
