<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: women | Martha Kelly]]></title>
  <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/categories/women/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-14T12:25:20-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Martha Kelly]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zoe Pablo: role model for women]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/08/01/zoe-pablo-role-model-for-young-women/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-01T09:23:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/08/01/zoe-pablo-role-model-for-young-women</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I found this article from Zoe Pablo, Olympic weight lifter, [ <a href="http://zoepablosmith.wordpress.com/2012/07/23/thanks-but-no-thanks/">article source</a> ] today and am so excited to share my favorite highlights with you. Women are marginalized by how they look and quite frankly <em>it's complete bullshit.</em></p>

<p><blockquote><p>The obvious choice of slander when talking about female weightlifting is “how unfeminine, girls shouldn’t be strong or have muscles, this is wrong”. And maybe they’re right… in the Victorian era.</p><footer><strong>Zoe Pablo</strong> <cite>Thanks (but No Thanks…)</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>we don’t lift weights in order to look hot, especially for the likes of men like that. What makes them think that we even WANT them to find us attractive? If you do, thanks very much, we’re flattered. But if you don’t, why do you really need to voice this opinion in the first place, and what makes you think we actually give a toss that you, personally, do not find us attractive? What do you want us to do? Shall we stop weightlifting, amend our diet in order to completely get rid of our ‘manly’ muscles, and become housewives in the sheer hope that one day you will look more favourably upon us and we might actually have a shot with you?!</p><footer><strong>Zoe Pablo</strong> <cite>Thanks (but No Thanks…)</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>xoxo</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
