<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Hacker School | Martha Kelly]]></title>
  <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/categories/hacker-school/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-11T10:52:40-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Martha Kelly]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[hacker school: day 90]]></title>
    <link href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/08/28/hacker-school-day-90/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-28T11:52:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/08/28/hacker-school-day-90</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_luxhb5MLBY1r52j4go1_500.jpg" /></p>

<p>I'm sitting in a cafe in Brooklyn, exhausted, disoriented, and happy. I'm thinking to myself, "Holy (enter your own choice expletive here). I did it, I finished Hacker School." I look back at my post recapping the first day and it's clear the rules of Hacker School permeate our lives, <em>and it feels completely natural</em>. Several Hacker Schoolers have told me how strange the outside world feels now.</p>

<p>During my time at Hacker School I've built my own CSS preprocessor in JS and static site generator in Python. I've contributed to BPython. I built deployment scripts with Boto/Fabric. I built a CLI chat server with sockets. I built full applications with frameworks I hadn't touched before (Backbone/Node/Django/etc), and <em>quickly</em>. I took a Stanford course on databases. I'm taking courses on Machine Learning now. There's no way I'm stopping, and I wouldn't have found this place without being inspired by my friends here.</p>

<p>Even more importantly, I learned how to believe in myself. I learned how to ask for help. I learned how to fight my own biases and those of the people around me.</p>

<h3>What I'll miss most:</h3>

<ul>
<li>Every single person here</li>
<li>Weekly gender and race discussions</li>
<li>Having deeply nerdy conversations with women I admire</li>
<li>Karaoke nights</li>
<li><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/etsylabs/4622257286/">Eatsy</a></li>
<li>IRC silliness</li>
<li>Epic email threads</li>
</ul>


<p>One thing I know, we'll bring the <a href="http://marthakelly.github.com/blog/2012/06/04/hacker-school-day-one/">"rules" of Hacker School</a> with us wherever we go.</p>

<p>After Hacker School I'm headed back to Nashville, a place I dearly love. This feeling of "otherness" is creeping in as I integrate back into the developer community there. A recent and popular developer conference had <a href="http://nashville.coderfaire.com/schedule/">one female speaker</a>. A company known for its great developer culture looks <a href="https://www.facebook.com/DevelopWithPurpose">eerily homogenous</a>. I have a lot of work to do here, and Hacker School has given me the skill set to do it.</p>

<p>So now, 90 days later, we go back out into the real world, egos in check, building code of consequence, and destroying stereotypes.</p>

<p>Thanks Sonali, Dave, Alan, Nick, Tom</p>

<p>Never Graduate!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
